Diop mss., 1963-2017 LMC 2944
Lilly Library
Diop mss.
1963-2017
2017
Lilly Library
Diop, Boubacar Boris, 1946-
LMC 2944
4 Boxes
The Diop mss., 1963-2017, consist of the notebooks, drafts, writings, correspondence, teaching materials, and born-digital materials of Senegalese author and journalist Boubacar Boris Diop, 1946-.
Access Restrictions
This collection is open for research.
Many collections are housed offsite; retrieval requires advance notice. Please make an appointment a minimum of one week in advance of your visit.
Biographical Note
Born in 1946 in Dakar, Boubacar Boris Diop is a Senegalese author, journalist, and teacher of philosophy and Wolof literature. In addition to founding Sol, a Senegalese newspaper, Diop served as editor-in-chief for Le Matin de Dakar and wrote as a columnist for the London magazine The New African. His novel Murambi was featured on the Zimbabwe International Book Fair's "100 Best African Books of the Twentieth Century."
Arrangement
The collection is organized into the following series: Personal, Legal and Financial, Printed, Correspondence, Writings, Journals and Notebooks, Teaching and Professional, and A/V and Born-Digital.
Scope and Content Note
The Personal series includes photographs and personal ephemera relating to Diop. Legal and Financial contains travel documents, bills, and contracts and agreements relating to publication. Printed includes publicity and writings about Diop as well as a sizeable quantity of programs, catalogs, and writings by others. Correspondence contains Diop's personal and professional correspondence arranged by decade. Writings includes manuscript notebooks and typescripts of Diop's published works, as well as essays and other writings. Journals and Notebooks contains personal journals (to-do lists, possible translation and teaching notes, narrative entries) as well as notebooks relating to journalistic articles and essays. Teaching and Professional includes lists of attendance, syllabi, and other teaching-related papers. A/V and Born-Digital contains Diop's hard drive as well as audio-visual materials.
Related Material
See Sembène mss., also located at the Lilly Library, Indiana University, Bloomington, Indiana.
Acquisition Information
Purchase: 2017
Diop, Boubacar Boris, 1946-
- I. PERSONAL
  - Drawings, undated (Box 1)
  - CV, undated (Box 1)
  - "Music details for CD's", October 2012 (Box 1)
  - Photographs, undated (Box 1)
  - Business cards, undated (Box 1)
  - Poem - "Pour Boris," author unknown, undated (Box 1)
  - Medical documents, 2013? (Box 1)
  - Badges and passes (Box 4)
- II. LEGAL AND FINANCIAL
  - Travel documents, 2013-2016? (Box 1)
  - Bills, receipts, and royalties, 2012-2015; (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - Contracts and agreements, 1986-2009 (Box 1)
  - Checkbook, undated (Box 1)
- III. PRINTED
  - Publicity and writings about Diop, 1985-2015; (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - Writings by others, 1987-2016; (8 folders) (Box 1)
  - Programs, brochures, and catalogs, 2010-2016; (Folders 1-2) (Box 1)
  - Programs, brochures, and catalogs, 2010-2016; (Folder 3) (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 2)
- IV. CORRESPONDENCE
  - 1960-1975 (Box 2)
  - 1980-1989 (Box 2)
  - 1990-1999 (Box 2)
  - 2000-2009 (Box 2)
  - 2010-2017 (Box 2)
  - Undated (Box 2)
- V. WRITINGS
  - Tambours de la Mémoire
    - Manuscript notebook, 1987 and 1990 (Box 4)
      Scope and Contents
      Blue notebook signed by Diop on front with graph-printed pages; approximately 270 pages written text; blue and black ink; primarily manuscript pages, starting with IV; includes a significant section of Part Two
    - Manuscript notebook, undated (Box 4)
      Red and black notebook with graph-printed pages; approximately 80 pages written blue and black ink; contains some manuscript pages, along with character sketches, hypotheses, outlines, and other information
    - Manuscript notebook, undated (Box 2)
    - Corrected typescript, undated (Box 2)
  - Traces de la Meute
    - Annotated typescript (printout), undated (Box 2)
    - Annotated typescript (form paper), undated (Box 2)
    - Notebooks, 1980-1990?; (6 folders) (Box 2)
    - Notebooks, 1980-1990?; 4 Folders (Box 4)
  - Le Cavalier et son Ombre
    - Manuscript notebook, 1980's? (Box 2)
  - Doomi Golo
    - Annotated typescript (Wolof), undated, (2 folders) (Box 2)
    - Typescript (English), undated (Box 2)
  - Other Writings
    - "Ibu Ndaw, Boroom Jamono," undated (Box 3)
    - Myriem chapter 1, undated (Box 3)
    - "Le Bourgeon," Culture et Loisirs Club, 1967? (Box 3)
    - Mémoire de Fin d'Etudes edited by Diop, 1991-1992 (Box 3)
    - Essays and prose, undated (Box 3)
- VI. JOURNALS AND NOTEBOOKS
  - Datebook, 1990 (Box 3)
  - "Cahier de Souvenirs", 1963-1964 (Box 3)
  - Notebooks from lycée, 1963-1964? (Box 3)
  - Journalism, essays, and teaching notes, 1980-1990?; (5 folders) (Box 3)
  - Personal journals, undated, (Folders 1-5) (Box 3)
  - Personal journals, undated, (Folder 6) (Box 4)
  - Loose notes, 1968-1989?; (2 folders) (Box 4)
- VII. TEACHING AND PROFESSIONAL
  - Attendance lists, undated (Box 4)
  - Student papers and projects, 2012-2013? (Box 4)
  - Université Gaston Berger, 2012? (Box 4)
  - Union Nationale des Ecrivains (UNES) - minutes, 6 November 1992 (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 4)
- VIII. A/V AND BORN-DIGITAL
  - Hard drive, undated (Box 4)
  - "Collection intégral de jazz," disc 7 of 10, CD (Box 4)
  - SAGEM F@st installation CD (Box 4)